Guide to the Parent-Teacher Association records for Eureka, Franklin, Roosevelt and Sehome schools 1917-1986
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
Parent-Teacher Association records for Eureka, Franklin, Roosevelt and Sehome schools
1917-1986
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0094bhamparentteacherassociation
Parent-Teacher Association
3 linear feet
The collection includes minutes, financial records, correspondence, and scrapbooks documenting the activities of Parent-Teacher Associations affiliated with Whatcom County schools.
The collection includes records generated by Parent-Teacher Associations (PTAs) affiliated with Franklin, Sehome, Roosevelt and Eureka schools in Whatcom County, Washington between 1917 and 1986. Materials include minutes, financial records, correspondence and scrapbooks.
The collection is open to the public.
Donated in 1997 by Krista Gordon of the Parent-Teacher Association of Roosevelt School.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Parent-Teacher Association--Washington (State)--Whatcom County
Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources
Community and school--Washington (State)--Whatcom County--History--Sources; Education--Washington (State)--Whatcom County--History--Sources; Parents' and teachers' associations--Washington (State)--Whatcom County--History--Sources; Scrapbooks--Washington (State)
Elementary and Secondary Education; Bellingham.
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Franklin PTA - accounts, 1947 September-1951 August (Box-folder 1/1)
- Franklin PTA - Secretaries' minutes, 1949 October-1951 May (Box-folder 1/2)
- Franklin PTA - bank statements and Treasurer's reports, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 1/3)
- Franklin PTA - bank statements and Treasurer's reports, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Franklin PTA - bank checks and deposits, 1936-1970 (Box-folder 1/5)
- Franklin PTA - bank check and deposit registers, 1939-1940; 1942-1960 (Box-folder 1/6)
- Franklin PTA - yearbooks, 1954-1971 (Box-folder 1/7)
- Sehome PTA - ledger, 1926-1940 (Box-folder 1/8)
- Bellingham PTA - Central Council, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 1/9)
- Eureka PTA - minutes, 1917-1924 (Box-folder 2/1)
- Eureka, and its successor, Roosevelt PTA - minutes, 1924-1930 (Box-folder 2/2)
- Eureka, and its successor, Roosevelt PTA - minutes, 1930-1939 (Box-folder 2/3)
- Roosevelt PTA - minutes, 1950-1956 (Box-folder 2/4)
- Roosevelt PTA - correspondence and miscellaneous items, 1933-1986 (Box-folder 2/5)
- Roosevelt PTA (Roosevelt Pre-School Group) - scrapbook, 1938-1942 (Volume 1)
- Roosevelt PTA - scrapbook, 1954-1955 (Volume 2)
- Franklin PTA - scrapbook, 1947 June-1948 May (Volume 3)
- Franklin PTA - scrapbook, 1948 September-1949 May (Volume 4)
- Franklin PTA - scrapbook, 1949 September-1950 May (Volume 5)
- Franklin PTA - scrapbook, 1950 September-1951 May (Volume 6)
- Franklin PTA - scrapbook, 1951 September-1952 May (Volume 7)
- Franklin PTA - scrapbook, 1952 September-1953 May (Volume 8)
- Franklin PTA - scrapbook, 1953 September-1954 May (Volume 9)
- Sehome PTA - scrapbook, 1932 October-1933 June (Volume 10)